Guide to the Yale College Book of Averages (Student Grade Books)
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Yale College book of averages (student grade books)
1813-1918
RU 584
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
5.75
(11 volumes)
The volumes document academic performance of students from the Classes of 1813-1918, Yale College.
Yale College (1887- )
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 9-F (YRG 9-F), Yale College student records.
Conditions Governing Access
Original materials are restricted due to fragile nature. Patrons must use microfilm HM 69.
Existence and Location of Copies
Available on microfilm (1,966 frames on 2 reels, 35mm.) from Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library. HM69.
Arrangement
The materials are arranged chronologically.
Scope and Contents
The volumes document academic performance of students from the Classes of 1813-1918, Yale College.
College students; Grade books; Yale College (1718-1887); Yale College (1887- ); Yale University -- Students
- Student grade books ("Book of Averages"), 1813-1905, 1916-1918; Accession 1940-A-006
  - Book of averages:
    - Classes of 1817-1841 (1813-1839) (Box 1, Folder 1, Reel 1U)
    - Classes of 1837-1868 (1833-1865) (Box 1, Folder 2, Reel 1U)
    - Classes of 1850-1865 (1846-1863) (Box 1, Folder 3, Reel 1U)
    - Classes of 1866-1883(1862-1880) (Box 1, Folder 4, Reel 1U)
    - By subject: Classes of 1865-1885 (1863-1882) (Box 2, Folder 5, Reel 1U)
  - Elementary average book for Senior Classes of 1864-1873 (Box 2, Folder 6, Reel 1U)
  - Book of averages, by subject:
    - Senior classes 1874-1881 (Box 2, Folder 6a, Reel 1U)
    - Classes of 1885-1889: Freshman and Sophomore years (Box 2, Folder 7, Reel 1U)
    - Classes of 1882-1890: Junior and Senior years (Box 2, Folder 7, Reel 1U)
    - Classes of 1891-1895 (1887-1893) (Box 3, Folder 8, Reel 2U)
    - Classes of 1896-1900 (1892-1899) (Box 3, Folder 9, Reel 2U)
    - Classes of 1901-1905 (Box 4, Folder 10, Reel 2U)
  - Book of Averages, Classes of 1916-1918 (Box 4, Folder 11, Reel 2U)